NYSUT Additional Records 5720
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
NYSUT Additional Records
1971-1981
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
New York State United Teachers (NYSUT)
5720
20 cubic feet
20 linear ft.
Records.
3123429
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, January 20, 2016
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 01, 2016
Biographical / Historical
New York State United Teachers (NYSUT) was created in 1972 by the merger of the New York State Teachers Association (NYSTA) and the United Teachers of New York (UTNY). NYSTA had been affiliated with the National Education Association (NEA), and UTNY with the American Federation of Teachers (AFT). UTNY was the statewide organization whose United Federation of Teachers (UFT), led by Albert Shanker, was the predominant teachers' union in New York City. In joining with United Teachers and affiliating with the AFT, NYSUT also became a member union of the AFL-CIO.
In 1976, NYSUT voted to disaffiliate with the NEA. Some locals left NYSUT and created the NYEA (New York Educators Association), which became the state affiliate for the NEA. In the early 1980s, NYEA changed its name to NEA-NY.
NYEA/NEA-NY viewed association with the AFL-CIO's industrial unions as undermining the professional image and independence of teachers. The two organizations also differed strongly on aspects of the governance structure, particularly with respect to ethnic minority representation, with NYSUT opposed to mandatory minimums. The rivalry between NYSUT and NYEA/NEA-NY in organizing new locals expended a great deal of resources for both labor organizations.
While competition with NYEA/NEA-NY was a constant focus of NYSUT's organizing efforts for teachers, NYSUT was also organizing college faculty members, nurses, and other non-teaching personnel. Once members were organized, NYSUT continued to advocate for teachers' and other workers' rights through contract support and legal services at the local level and political involvement at the state and federal levels, supporting candidates and legislation that protected funding, due process, and working conditions.
NEA-N Y merged with NYSUT in 2006, by which time NYSUT had grown to more than half a million members, becoming the largest union in New York State.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5293: New York State Teachers Association Records
Teachers' unions -- New York (State) -- New York -- Sources; New York State United Teachers.
3123429
- Meeting 2/2 and 2/3 1973 NYSUT (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Representative Assembly March 23-25, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Finance Committee (NYSUT) March 14, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Administrative/Executive Comm. (NYSUT) Feb. 14, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- February 2-3, 1973 Joint Board of Directors (Box 1, Folder 5)
- January 16, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Administrative/Executive Comm. (NYSUT) December 12, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- July 6, 1973 Executive Board NYSUT (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Executive Committee 6/15/73, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Board of Directors and Executives Board Meeting 5/6/73, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Administrative/Executive Comm. (NYSUT) March 20, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- New York State AFL-CIO Convention Sept., 1973 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- August 25-26 Board of Directors Meeting NYSUT, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- President's Conference August 1973 NYSUT (Box 1, Folder 14)
- October 10, 1973 Executive Committee (Box 1, Folder 15)
- September 11, 1973 Meeting Executive Committee (NYSUT) (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Executive Board (NYSUT) January 15, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Presidents Conference (NYSUT) January 11-13, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Executive Committee (NYSUT) December 4, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Election Committee for R.A. March 21, - March 24, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Executive Board - March 15, 16, 1974 - Americana Inn, Albany (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Executive Board 2/13/74 NYSUT, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Board of Directors January 25 - January 26, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Executive Committee 6/13/74, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Board of Directors Meeting 5/10, 5/11/74, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Bd. Of Directors September 13-14, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Montreal Convention 1974 NYSUT (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Credentials Comm: Buffalo, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- 11/7/74 Executive Board Meeting Including Political Action Mat., 1974 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- 10/17/74 Executive Board Including Railroad Proposition, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Executive Board of Directors Dec. 6-7, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Executive Committee August 20, 1975 (NYSUT) (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Executive Committee 9/18/75 NYSUT, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Executive Comm. 10/16/75 (NYSUT), 1975 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Jeannette Dilorenzo, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Representative Assembly March 20-23, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Teachers Unions, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Executive Committee May 1, 1975 (NYSUT) (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Executive Committee May 1, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Board of Directors March 14 - March 15, 1975 (NYSUT) (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Board of Directors NYSUT September 26-27, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Board of Directors March 14-15, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Executive Committee (NYSUT) March 11, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Bd of Directors 1/24-1/25/75, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Board of Directors (NYSUT), 1975 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Executive Bd. 1/24/75, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Executive Board 6/5/75 (NYSUT), 1975 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Jeannette Dilorenzo, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Jeannette DiLorenzo, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Jeannette Dilorenzo, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- NYSUT Confidential, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Representative Assembly, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Executive Board 2/11/76, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Jeannette Dilorenzo, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Jeannette Dilorenzo, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Jeannette Dilorenzo, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Board of Directors, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- March 1977 Representative Assembly (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Sept. 30 - Oct. 1, 1977 Bd. Of Directors (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Jan. 6, 1977 Executive Committee (Box 5, Folder 3)
- April 28, 1977 Executive Committee (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Exec. Committee + Bd. Of Directors, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Ex. Board - Budget Problems June 2, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Nov. 18-19, 1977 Bd. Of Directors (Box 6, Folder 1)
- May 13-14, 1977 Bd. Of Directors (Box 6, Folder 2)
- May 13-14, 1977 Bd. Of Directors (Box 6, Folder 3)
- March 18-19, 1977 Bd of Directors (Box 6, Folder 4)
- United Teachers of New York State, 1971-1975 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- UTNY, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- NYSUT Bd./Director, 1973-1974 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- American Federation of Teachers, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- NYSUT, 1972-1974 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Board of Education (1967-1971), 1967-1973 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Bd./Directors from 1976-1979 closed NYSUT, 1976-1981 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- N.Y.S.U.T. Arbitrators, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- N.Y.S.U.T. Board of Directors, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- N.Y.S.U.T. Board of Directors, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- N.Y.S.U.T. Board of Regents, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- N.Y.S.U.T. Budget, 1975-1976 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- N.Y.S.U.T. Colleges, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- N.Y.S.U.T. Constitution, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- N.Y.S.U.T. Consumer Price Index, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- N.Y.S.U.T. Cope, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- N.Y.S.U.T. Cope, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- N.Y.S.U.T. Cornell University, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 11)
- N.Y.S.U.T. Toni Cortese, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 12)
- CPE, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 13)
- N.Y.S.U.T. Kennedy Deedy, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 14)
- N.Y.S.U.T. Vito De Leonardis, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 15)
- N.Y.S.U.T. Vito De Leonardis, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 16)
- N.Y.S.U.T. - Booklets Educational Issues, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 17)
- Election District #17 N.Y.S.U.T., 1975-1976 (Box 9, Folder 18)
- N.Y.S.U.T. Elections, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 19)
- N.Y.S.U.T. Executive Committee, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 20)
- N.Y.S.U.T. Executive Committee, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 21)
- N.Y.S.U.T. General, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- N.Y.S.U.T. Grievance Material, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- N.Y.S.U.T. Tom Hobart - President, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- N.Y.S.U.T. Ned Hopkins, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- N.Y.S.U.T. Insurance (Box 10, Folder 5)
- N.Y.S.U.T. Eugene M. Kaufman, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- N.Y.S.U.T. Eugene M. Kaufman, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- N.Y.S.U.T. Jules Kolodny, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Legislation, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 9)
- N.Y.S.U.T. Legislation, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 10)
- N.Y.S.U.T. Mailgram - Incoming, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 11)
- N.Y.S.U.T. Mailgram - Incoming (Box 10, Folder 12)
- N.Y.S.U.T. Memorandum, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 13)
- N.Y.S.U.T. N.Y. Students for Effective Education, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 14)
- N.Y.S.U.T. N.Y. Students for Effective Education, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 15)
- N.Y. Students for Effective Education N.Y.S.U.T., 1976 (Box 10, Folder 16)
- N.Y.S.U.T. Our State, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 17)
- N.Y.S.U.T. Professional Staff Association, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 18)
- N.Y.S.U.T. Professional Staff Association, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 19)
- N.Y.S.U.T. Public Relations (Box 10, Folder 20)
- N.Y.S.U.T. Public Relations, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 21)
- N.Y.S.U.T. Ramapo #2 Teacher Assoc., 1976 (Box 10, Folder 22)
- N.Y.S.U.T. Representative Assembly, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 23)
- Retirement N.Y.S.U.T., 1976 (Box 10, Folder 24)
- N.Y.S.U.T. Retirement, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 25)
- Dan Sanders N.Y.S.U.T., 1976 (Box 10, Folder 26)
- N.Y.S.U.T. Jim Sandner, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 27)
- N.Y.S.U.T. Second Step Appeals, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 28)
- Shanker, Al., 1976 (Box 10, Folder 29)
- N.Y.S.U.T. Albert Shanker Exec. Vice President, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 30)
- N.Y.S.U.T. Social Security, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 31)
- N.Y.S.U.T. Dean E. Streiff, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 32)
- N.Y.S.U.T. Dean E. Streiff, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 33)
- N.Y.S.U.T. - Teacher Education Conference Board - Newsletter, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 34)
- N.Y.S.U.T. Telegram - Outgoing, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 35)
- Minutes, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Minutes, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Minutes, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Minutes, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Minutes, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Minutes, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Minutes, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Minutes, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Minutes, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 12, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 12)
- Financial, 1978-1979 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Financial, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Financial, 1976-1977 (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Financial, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Financial, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Financial, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Legislative Docs, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Legislative Docs, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Legislative Docs, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 9)
- Legislative Docs, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 10)
- Legislative Docs, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 11)
- Publications, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 12)
- Publications, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 13)
- Publications, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Publications, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Publications, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Publications, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Publications, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 5)
- Publications, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 6)
- Publications, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 7)
- Publications, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 8)
- Publications, 1977-1978 (Box 14, Folder 9)
- Publications, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 10)
- Publications, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 11)
- Publications, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 12)
- AFL-CIO Convention (New York State), 1976 (Box 15, Folder 1)
- NEA Report on the 58th Annual Convention of AFT, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 2)
- AFT Convention, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 3)
- AFT Convention, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 4)
- AFT Convention, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 5)
- Application for Rechartering of NEA Affiliates (NYSUT), 1974 (Box 15, Folder 6)
- AFT Convention, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 7)
- AFT Publication, 1977-1978 (Box 15, Folder 8)
- AFT - Publications, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 9)
- Accountability (NEA), 1974 (Box 15, Folder 10)
- ADCOM (UTNY), 1971-1973 (Box 15, Folder 11)
- Adopt a Teacher Program (NEA), 1974 (Box 15, Folder 12)
- Affairs Committee (AFT), 1972 (Box 15, Folder 13)
- Affiliates Sub-Committee (NYSUT), 1976 (Box 15, Folder 14)
- African Relief Fund (AFT), 1975 (Box 15, Folder 15)
- American Association of University Professors, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 16)
- American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations Convention, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 17)
- Arbitration and Legal Services NYCT (Box 15, Folder 18)
- Assembly and Senate Committee (NYSUT), 1973 (Box 15, Folder 19)
- Bicentennial (NYSUT), 1976 (Box 15, Folder 20)
- Bd. Of Directors (NYSTA), 1977 (Box 15, Folder 21)
- Bd. Of Directors (NYSTA), 1976 (Box 15, Folder 22)
- Board of Regents (NYSUT), 1977 (Box 15, Folder 23)
- COPE (UTNY), 1972 (Box 16, Folder 1)
- CBTE (NYSUT), 1975 (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Charter Flights (NYSUT) (Box 16, Folder 3)
- Class Size Study, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 4)
- Colleges (States), 1972 (Box 16, Folder 5)
- Committee on Committees (NYSUT), 1974 (Box 16, Folder 6)
- Committee on Election Districts (NYSUT), 1973 (Box 16, Folder 7)
- Committee on Striking Locals (NYSUT), 1974 (Box 16, Folder 8)
- Communications to Locals (UTNY), 1972 (Box 16, Folder 9)
- Communications to Local Presidents NYCT, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 10)
- Community Colleges Under SUNY-NYSUT, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 11)
- Competency Based Teacher Education (NYSUT), 1975 (Box 16, Folder 12)
- Congress (How They Voted) (AFL-CIO), 1973 (Box 16, Folder 13)
- Congressional Conference on Inflation - HEW (NEA), 1974 (Box 16, Folder 14)
- Consolidation Resolution (NYCT), 1973 (Box 16, Folder 15)
- Constitution (Proposed) NEA (Box 16, Folder 16)
- Constitutional Amendments (Proposed) (AFT), 1972 (Box 16, Folder 17)
- Consumer Price Index (NYCT), 1976 (Box 16, Folder 18)
- Convention (AFT), 1977 (Box 16, Folder 19)
- Convention - NYSUT - 1973 (Box 16, Folder 20)
- Convention - NYSUT, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 21)
- Convention - NEA - 1974 (Box 16, Folder 22)
- NEA Chicago 1974 Convention (Box 16, Folder 23)
- Convention - NEA - 1974 (Box 16, Folder 24)
- Convention Material (8/22/72) (UTNY), 1972 (Box 16, Folder 25)
- Correspondence (UTNY), 1972 (Box 16, Folder 26)
- Cortese, Toni (NYSUT), 1974 (Box 16, Folder 27)
- Council of AFL-CIO Unions for Professional Employees, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 28)
- Court of Appeals Opinion - NYSUT, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 29)
- Credentials Comm. 1972-73 (NYSUT), 1972-1973 (Box 16, Folder 30)
- Credentials Comm. 1972-73 (NYSUT), 1972-1973 (Box 16, Folder 31)
- Credentials Comm. 1972-73 (NYSUT), 1972-1973 (Box 16, Folder 32)
- Credentials Comm. 1972-1973 (NYSUT) (Box 16, Folder 33)
- Miscellaneous, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 1)
- Challengers, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 2)
- Credentials Comm. 1974 (NYSUT) (Box 17, Folder 3)
- Credentials Comm. 1975 NYSUT (Box 17, Folder 4)
- Credentials Comm. 1975 - NYSUT (Box 17, Folder 5)
- Credentials Comm. 1975 NYSUT (Box 17, Folder 6)
- Credentials Comm. - NYSUT - 1976 (Box 17, Folder 7)
- Credentials Comm. NYSUT - 1976 (Box 17, Folder 8)
- Crisis Commission on NYC Schools (AFT), 1975 (Box 17, Folder 9)
- Defense Fund Expenditures NYCT (Box 17, Folder 10)
- Delegates (NYSUT), 1972 (Box 17, Folder 11)
- Democratic State Committee (Democratic Leader) NYSUT, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 12)
- Dental Hygiene Teachers (NYCT), 1979 (Box 17, Folder 13)
- Department of School Nurses (NEA), 1974 (Box 17, Folder 14)
- Detroit Public Schools Desegregation Case (AFT), 1971 (Box 17, Folder 15)
- Disaffiliation (NYSUT), 1975-1976 (Box 17, Folder 16)
- Dues (NYSUT), 1977 (Box 17, Folder 17)
- Dushane Fund (NEA), 1975 (Box 17, Folder 18)
- EEO Newsletter NYCT, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 19)
- Eastern Regional Conference (AFT), 1973 (Box 17, Folder 20)
- Educational Conference Board (State), 1971-1976 (Box 17, Folder 21)
- Educational Issues (NYSUT), 1973 (Box 17, Folder 22)
- Election Districts Communications (NYSUT), 1976 (Box 17, Folder 23)
- Election District Reports (NYSUT), 1974 (Box 17, Folder 24)
- Election Districts (NYCT), 1974 (Box 17, Folder 25)
- Election Procedures Committee (NYSTA), 1972 (Box 17, Folder 26)
- Empire State Report (NYSUT), 1976 (Box 17, Folder 27)
- Empire State Federation of Teachers Expense Sheet (Box 17, Folder 28)
- Energy Crisis (NYSUT), 1973 (Box 17, Folder 29)
- Estimates of School Statistics, 1973-74 (NEA), 1973-1974 (Box 17, Folder 30)
- Executive Board, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 31)
- Executive Committee (NEA), 1975 (Box 17, Folder 32)
- Executive Council Minutes (UTNY), 1972 (Box 17, Folder 33)
- Executive Council Proceedings (AFT), 1973 (Box 17, Folder 34)
- Executive Vice President, Duties NYCT (Box 17, Folder 35)
- Fact-Finding Commission on Serving Local (AFT), 1972 (Box 18, Folder 1)
- Fair Dismissal Law (NYSUT), 1972 (Box 18, Folder 2)
- Federal Bargaining Law (National), 1974 (Box 18, Folder 3)
- Financing A National Standard of Education (NYCT) (Box 18, Folder 4)
- Financial, 1974-1975 (Box 18, Folder 5)
- Budget Crisis Material (UTNY), 1971-1973 (Box 18, Folder 6)
- Financial Budget (NYSUT), 1975 (Box 18, Folder 7)
- Financial Jeannette Dilorenzo, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 8)
- NYSUT Financial Budget (1975-1979) (Box 18, Folder 9)
- Financial Statement 9/71 - 12/71, 1971 (Box 18, Folder 10)
- Accounting Reports NYCT, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 11)
- Monthly Statement On 1. Per Capita (Dues) 2. Income and Expenses, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 12)
- Finance Committee UTNY, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 13)
- Joint Finance Meetings, 1971-1974 (Box 18, Folder 14)
- Delinquency Notices Financials, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 15)
- Financial Statement Extra Copies, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 16)
- Per Capita (AFT) May 1969 on (Box 18, Folder 17)
- Jean Gordon Memoranda Related to Files (3/4/72) NYS Empire State, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 18)
- Financial Information and Financial Problems and Budget (1972) (Box 18, Folder 19)
- Fleischman Report (NYCT), 1973 (Box 18, Folder 20)
- Florida Teachers National, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 21)
- Florida - Pat Tornillo, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 22)
- For the Record (NEA), 1974 (Box 18, Folder 23)
- Guidance Counselors (AFT), 1973 (Box 18, Folder 24)
- Guide for Legislative Action and State CB Laws (AFT) (Box 18, Folder 25)
- Harris Poll, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 26)
- Harrison Teachers Association (NYSUT), 1973 (Box 18, Folder 27)
- Health and Dental Insurance Fund (NYSUT), 1973 (Box 18, Folder 28)
- Herndon (NEA), 1975 (Box 18, Folder 29)
- Hicksville Federation Committee (Presidency Controversy) UTNY, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 30)
- Hotline NYSUT, 1973 (Box 18, Folder 31)
- Housing and Urban Development, 1973 (Box 18, Folder 32)
- Human Relations Council Annual Report (NYSTA), 1973 (Box 18, Folder 33)
- Human Relations Programs (NEA), 1974 (Box 18, Folder 34)
- Humanism in Education (NYSUT), 1975 (Box 18, Folder 35)
- Illinois Education Association (NEA) (Box 18, Folder 36)
- Income Tax (NYSUT), 1974 (Box 18, Folder 37)
- Instruction and Professional Development (NEA), 1974 (Box 18, Folder 38)
- Insurance Trust (NYSUT), 1973 (Box 18, Folder 39)
- Interim Governance Structure of NYCT, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 40)
- International Relations Comm., 1973 (Box 18, Folder 41)
- International Relations Comm., 1973 (Box 18, Folder 42)
- Japan National, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 1)
- Joint Administrative Committee (NYCT), 1972 (Box 19, Folder 2)
- Judicial Committee (NYCT), 1973 (Box 19, Folder 3)
- Kugler, Phil (AFT), 1975 (Box 19, Folder 4)
- Landrum-Griffin Act Reports (NYSUT), 1973 (Box 19, Folder 5)
- Legal Department UTNY, 1972 (Box 19, Folder 6)
- Legal Dept., Status of Outstanding Cases (NYCT), 1972 (Box 19, Folder 7)
- Legal Services (NYSUT), 1974 (Box 19, Folder 8)
- Legislative Program, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 9)
- Legislative Program, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 10)
- Legislative Program, 1976-1977 (Box 19, Folder 11)
- Legislative Reports (AFT), 1972 (Box 19, Folder 12)
- Legislative Reports (1972) UTNY (Box 19, Folder 13)
- Letterhead NYCT (Box 19, Folder 14)
- Local District Defaults NYSUT, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 15)
- Local President Information (NYSUT), 1975 (Box 19, Folder 16)
- Maryland State Teachers Association, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 17)
- Membership Promotion Responsibilities NYCT (Box 19, Folder 18)
- Membership (NEA), 1974 (Box 19, Folder 19)
- Membership Reports NYCT, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 20)
- Merger (NEA), 1975 (Box 19, Folder 21)
- Merger - UTNY/NYSTA and Joint Meetings, 1972 (Box 19, Folder 22)
- Michigan Accountability System (NEA), 1974 (Box 19, Folder 23)
- Minority Groups and Women in Instructional Materials NYCT, 1972 (Box 19, Folder 24)
- Minimum Wage (NYSUT), 1973 (Box 19, Folder 25)
- National Association of Professional Educators (NEA), 1974 (Box 19, Folder 26)
- National Collective Bargaining (AFT), 1973 (Box 19, Folder 27)
- National conference of Urban Education Association (NEA), 1974 (Box 19, Folder 28)
- National Council for Effective Schools (AFT), 1973 (Box 19, Folder 29)
- Neo Bargaining Unit Personnel NYCT, 1973-1974 (Box 19, Folder 30)
- New York State AFL-CIO, 1973-1976 (Box 19, Folder 31)
- NYS Fed. Of Teachers - Convention - 1970 (Box 19, Folder 32)
- Norta News NYCT, 1972 (Box 19, Folder 33)
- Obituaries (NYSUT), 1977 (Box 19, Folder 34)
- Pension/Retirement, 1972-1977 (Box 19, Folder 35)
- Per Capita (NYSUT), 1977 (Box 19, Folder 36)
- Personnel List (Combined) NYCT, 1972-1973 (Box 19, Folder 37)
- Personnelity (NYSUT), 1975-1976 (Box 19, Folder 38)
- Policies of the Board of Directors Handbook (NYSTA), 1970 (Box 19, Folder 39)
- P.S.A. (NYSTA), 1974 (Box 19, Folder 40)
- Political Action, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 41)
- Public Employees Federation (NYSUT), 1975 (Box 19, Folder 42)
- Publications, 1972 (Box 19, Folder 43)
- Reid, Ogden, 1974 (Box 20, Folder 1)
- Reimbursement for Field Services for NYC Region (NYCT) (Box 20, Folder 2)
- Resolutions (UTNY), 1971 (Box 20, Folder 3)
- Retirement Convention Committee (NYSUT), 1974 (Box 20, Folder 4)
- "Right to Work" Laws, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 5)
- Salary Schedule Data (NYSUT), 1972-1973 (Box 20, Folder 6)
- School Boards (NYSSBA), 1977 (Box 20, Folder 7)
- Search (Project) NYCT, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 8)
- Special Education (NYSUT), 1977 (Box 20, Folder 9)
- Staff Training and Development NYCT, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 10)
- Statement of Operations and Net Worth (UTNY), 1972 (Box 20, Folder 11)
- 1972 Strikes NYCT (Box 20, Folder 12)
- Student NYSTA, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 13)
- Task Force (NYCT) (Certification), 1972 (Box 20, Folder 14)
- Teacher Education Conference (NYCT), 1972 (Box 20, Folder 15)
- Teacher Leaders Institute NYSUT, 1974 (Box 20, Folder 16)
- Teacher Preparation and Certification (NYCT), 1972 (Box 20, Folder 17)
- Teacher Rights Fund Committee (NYSTA), 1972 (Box 20, Folder 18)
- Teachers' Retirement Board NYSUT, 1973 (Box 20, Folder 19)
- Tenure (Lieberman Article), 1972 (Box 20, Folder 20)
- Tenure +, 1976 (Box 20, Folder 21)
- Tenured Teacher Hearings, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 22)
- Transmittal of Dues and Membership Information (Procedures) NYCT, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 23)
- Treasurers (UTNY), 1972-1973 (Box 20, Folder 24)
- Vote/Cope, 1974 (Box 20, Folder 25)
- Wage Price Freeze (UTNY), 1972 (Box 20, Folder 26)
- Washington Newsletter (AFT), 1974 (Box 20, Folder 27)